<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Native Human Experience</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Dhruv Yadav </description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:18:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Shame and Suffering of a Sober Sunday </title>
		<link>/hello-world/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dhruv Yadav]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 09:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another trip &#8216;around the sun. Another year spent juicing the last drops from the overworked well of dopamine. I have been down with fatigue and headaches the past couple of days, as my body tires of another cycle of indulgence. The screen, work, booze, smoke, exercise—all rejected, all impossible—so I sit in bed, unmade, much [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="padding-top:0;padding-right:var(--wp--preset--spacing--30);padding-bottom:0;padding-left:var(--wp--preset--spacing--30)">Another trip &#8216;around the sun. Another year spent juicing the last drops from the overworked well of dopamine. I have been down with fatigue and headaches the past couple of days, as my body tires of another cycle of indulgence. The screen, work, booze, smoke, exercise—all rejected, all impossible—so I sit in bed, unmade, much like the man at the moment. This has been a result of a 3-day bender starting last Friday—but the root cause started a minute back. For the first time in months, I’ve done nothing. The disgust of my brain, left unchecked, has run rampant. No distractions to quell my anxiety, no work to offer validation, no vices to numb the stress, and no routines to counter the toll my habits have taken.</p>



<p>Early Christian hermits, <em>the desert fathers</em>, had a word for this: <em>acedia</em>, an existential malaise that plagued monks when faced with idleness. Acedia was often seen as the “<em>demon of the noontime</em>”—when the work paused, they wrestled with this demon, describing it as a paralyzing force that left them restless, despairing, and questioning their purpose. Acedia was not simply boredom—it was a profound confrontation with the void, an encounter with the self without the usual distractions to obscure it. Their writings detail how this state could lead to disgust with the self and the environment—feelings the modern machine has made a dedicated effort to avoid. What once was a natural human experience—a pause in time—has been digitized, repackaged, and served as a 10-second anesthetic. A fleeting escape, now a product designed to deliver these microdoses of dopamine to soothe our restlessness in exchange for a deeper disconnection.</p>



<p>Eight hours in, as the back pain worsened, strangely, my restlessness finally gave way to clarity. It was a clarity, however, tainted—a brutal revelation of the time I had squandered—high, high on distractions, lost in films that didn’t move me, trapped in a job I despised, breakups not processed, and haunted by the memories of careless remarks made that now make my stomach twist in shame. I am sure there is a parable to be made with my previous argument on the listlessness of the desert fathers.</p>



<p>The Desert Fathers fled into the wilderness, seeking solace from the distractions of the world, but found instead a mirror of their own inner turmoil. They fled into solitude not only to escape the noise of society but to confront something far more insidious—the chaos within themselves. What they encountered, however, was a disorienting stillness, where the usual distractions—work, socializing, comforts—were absent, and only their own restless minds remained. <em>A</em> force crept in when the external noise faded, exposing the emptiness of their inner lives. It wasn’t the silence of peace they encountered, but the noise of their own dissatisfaction and unease.</p>



<p>Much like them, I find myself here, in the strange quiet of my own making. As the distractions fade—no work to do, no distractions to numb the discomfort—the mind begins to turn inward, and with it comes a clarity that feels more like a weight than a revelation. True solitude does not seem to bring instant peace or enlightenment; rather, it forces you to face the rawness of existence—the petty regrets, the unresolved guilt, the gnawing sense of time slipping away.</p>



<p>The disquieting sense of inertia continues to morph as I go deeper into the night, and sleep remains a step ahead. Pain pulses through my neck and head as I lay in the dark room, burritoed in my blanket. There is no comfort to be found—the room is simultaneously too cold to have my feet out but too warm to be covered up completely. There is no diplomacy between the blanket and the room. I think of Raoul Duke, lost in Vegas, having woken up from a bender of unimaginable proportions and dealing with the confrontation of the aftermath of a hollow life lived in a blur. I don’t want that for myself. <em>Too late, too late</em>—maybe not. Maybe.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="is-style-default has-medium-font-size">“I felt the familiar wave of nausea rise in my throat. A feeling I had known too well by now, like some kind of strange animal crawling up my spine. But it was different this time. A sudden clarity, a desperate urgency to make sense of all of this. I thought about the American dream, about the madness of everything we had done so far. And for a moment, I felt like I was seeing it all for what it really was—<em>too late, too late</em>.”</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li class="has-medium-font-size">Hunter Thompson, <em>Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas</em></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>



<p>As the first slivers of light pierce through the curtains, there is no grand change in my circumstances, no miraculous transformation. But it does bring with it a certain calmness—a quiet but undeniable confrontation. I cannot stay suspended in this dissonance of awareness and loathing. The day beckons as it always has, with a promise of nothing more than the next step forward. Perhaps the key is not to seek resolution or the end of restlessness, maybe just to accept its presence, quietly, as I move forward—without grand epiphanies or promises, but with a steady sense of acknowledgment, and a calm, uncertain step into the day. I stumble out of bed in pain to make some coffee and start the next day of this misery.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Third Floor Symphony</title>
		<link>/third-floor-symphony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dhruv Yadav]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=25</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Horns are going off competitively, each car trying to outdo the other in pitch and persistence—some sharp and abrupt, others drawn-out and wailing, creating a symphony so chaotic you have no choice but to wake up. I live on the third floor above a restaurant on a commercial street in Bangalore, alarms are for people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Horns are going off competitively, each car trying to outdo the other in pitch and persistence—some sharp and abrupt, others drawn-out and wailing, creating a symphony so chaotic you have no choice but to wake up. I live on the third floor above a restaurant on a commercial street in Bangalore, alarms are for people living in apartment complexes; birdsong, for those near parks. I don’t complain—this chaos saves me from the true villain: Bangalore’s treacherous traffic. That trade-off, I assure you, is worth the morning headache.</p>



<p>I stumble out of bed and as usual my slippers play the usual mischief; they change sides whilst I slept. It&#8217;s almost reassuring in its predictability &#8211; I hate being barefoot in the washroom! I am a creature of habit for all the basic human experiences, my mornings, predictable as clockwork &#8211; indistinguishable from one to next. I find great solace in ritualising it &#8211; helps me gather myself for the long day ahead.</p>



<p>As I step out the floor feels cool to touch as a contrast to the tippy toe gymnastics I just did. The sun is sunning today as the kitchen beckons, and I shuffle toward it, drawn by the promise of caffeine and the quiet solace of a ritual that never fails me.</p>



<p>The kettle hums its familiar tune as I contemplate the cupboard—a shrine to my morning choices. Blue Tokai’s Hidden Falls Estate or the bright, floral Chelchele from Ethiopia? My hand hovers, indecisive yet hopeful, and finally settles on Chelchele. Its promise of vibrant berries and floral notes feels right for today. But life, in its infinite mischief, throws its curveball—the French press, my trusted companion, sits forlornly in the sink, coated in the remnants of yesterday’s brew. Alas, Chelchele retreats, replaced by the steady reassurance of Blue Tokai and my aeropress.</p>



<p>Such is life, I think, as I setup the aeropress on my counter. Plans, no matter how small, are rearranged by the day’s whims. But perhaps that’s the charm—the unscripted moments that steer us toward unexpected pleasures. The water comes to a rolling boil, an impatient crescendo, before I silence it, letting it rest for just a breath. As I pour it over the grounds, the coffee blooms in a tender swell—a ritual as fleeting as it is profound. And then, it arrives: a fragrance so vivid, so achingly pure, it seems to awaken something primal within me. It’s not the caffeine—no, that’s merely an afterthought—but this sacred aroma, this olfactory hymn, that truly pulls me from the fog of sleep and into the day.</p>



<p>I let it seep for a few minutes and turn to worship at the altar of the mobile phone gods. It is, as always, an exercise in futility—friends, dispatching reels of absurdity from their porcelain thrones; managers firing off emails with the urgency of kings, no doubt from the same throne; parents, ever diligent, delivering their dutiful good mornings with toilet-bound solemnity. Zepto, intrudes as a faux-friend, cajoling me toward some unnecessary purchase. And there it is, the final offering: the stock market, once again wallowing in its own shitter. Such is modern devotion, banalities masquerading as connection.</p>



<p>It’s been fifteen minutes, and I’ve completely forgotten about the coffee, ensnared by the seductive clutches of my phone. Finally, I set it aside, guiltily making my way to the kitchen. The aeropress awaits, its plunger perched precariously, ready for the final act. I push it down, slowly, deliberately, listening to the gentle drip of coffee hitting the cup below. The aroma rises, potent and audacious, hijacking my senses—an olfactory orgasm.</p>



<p>With coffee in hand, along with my smokes and the morning paper, I walk to the balcony. The hall stretches before me, a passage not just to the balcony but to a moment of clarity. I settle into my chair, a willing spectator to the animation of the city below—hustlers, dreamers, and the resigned, all stitched into the fabric of Bangalore’s morning bustle. The weather, as always, is a gift—a brisk wind, cool and rejuvenating, paired with the sun’s gentle caress. The clouds hang immense, their grandeur almost cartoonish—plucked straight from an episode of <em>The Simpsons</em>.</p>



<p>I light my smoke, the first drag of an exhale of yesterday’s remnants. Then comes the sip—the coffee’s warm embrace, a liquid affirmation down my throat that my ritual has borne its reward. In that moment, as the universe aligns with the rhythm of my morning, I feel it: everything will be okay today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
